George Lardner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Subject File, 1923-1997 (Box 1-285)
  - Floodgate (Daniel J. Flood)
    - Airlie Foundation
      - Research material
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1970-1978, undated, (5 folders) (Box 78)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1967, 1977-1978, undated
    - Anthra-Penn Community Development Corp., 1974-1978, undated
    - Articles and correspondence, 1978, undated
    - Bahamas and Haiti, 1971-1978, undated
    - Dash, Samuel, "Evaluation of the Special Prosecutor's Office of Philadelphia," 1977 (Box 79)
    - Elko, Stephen B.
      - Articles, undated
      - Correspondence, 1978, undated
      - Notes, 1978, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1972-1977, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972-1978, undated
    - Fleming, Deryl
      - Diary entries, 1975-1976
      - Interview, undated
    - Hahnemann Hospital, Philadelphia, Pa.
      - Articles and correspondence, 1978, undated
      - Notes, undated
      - Research material
        - Financial, 1975-1978, undated, (2 folders)
        - Legal documents, undated (Box 80)
        - Miscellaneous, 1973-1978, undated, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1978, undated
    - Interviews, 1977-1978, undated, (2 folders)
    - Marston, David W.
      - Articles, 1978, undated
      - Correspondence, 1978, undated
      - Notes, 1978, undated
      - Research material
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1976-1978, undated, (4 folders)
    - Notes, 1977-1978, undated, (3 folders) (Box 81)
    - Pinter, Leib, 1978
    - Research material
      - Freedom of Information Act requests
        - Agency for International Development, 1978
        - Agriculture Department, 1978
        - Community Services Administration, 1978, (2 folders)
        - Defense Department, 1978
        - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, 1978
        - Housing and Urban Development, Department of, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 82)
        - Labor Department, 1978
        - Miscellaneous, 1978
      - Miscellany, 1969-1978, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973-1978, undated
    - Resorts International, 1978, undated
    - Rubino, Theodore S. A., 1977
  - Ford, Gerald R., assassination attempt, 1975, undated
  - Foreign investors
    - Articles, 1966
    - Correspondence, interviews, and notes, 1966, undated (Box 83)
  - Foreign investors
    - Research material, 1963-1966
  - Freedom of Information Act
    - Initial series
      - Articles, 1976, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1976
      - Interviews, 1976, (2 folders)
      - Notes, 1976, undated
      - Research material
        - Agriculture Department, 1975-1976
        - Appropriations, 1966, 1976, undated
        - Backdoor legislation, 1975-1976 (Box 84)
        - Center for National Security Studies and allied organizations, 1975-1979, undated
        - Central Intelligence Agency, 1975-1980
        - Church of Scientology, 1975-1978, undated, (3 folders)
        - Commerce Department, undated
        - Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 1975-1976, undated
        - Cooper, Richard M., report, 1973
        - Corporate usage, 1975, undated
        - Court rulings, 1976
        - Defense Department, 1975-1980
        - Executive orders and regulations, 1972-1977, undated (Box 85)
        - Exemption claims, 1975-1976
        - Exemption laws, 1975, undated
        - Federal Bar Association conference, 1976, undated
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, crash program, 1976-1977, undated
        - Federal Trade Commission bill, 1980
        - Food and Drug Administration, 1975-1976
        - Ford, Gerald, veto message and legislative reports, 1974-1975
        - Fund for Constitutional Government suits, 1972-1975, undated
        - General Services Administration, 1976 (Box 86)
        - Holly v. U.S. Customs Service, 1976, undated
        - Housing and Urban Development Department, 1975-1976, undated
        - Interior Department, 1975-1976, undated, (2 folders)
        - Internal Revenue Service and the Treasury Department, 1975-1976, undated
        - Justice Department and FBI
          - Attorney general's guidelines, 1967, 1975-1977
          - General, 1975-1980, undated
        - Kennedy, Edward Moore, 1975
        - Lawsuits (Box 87)
          - Agency for International Development, lawsuit over fees, 1975-1976, undated
          - Miscellaneous, 1975-1980, undated
          - Military Audit Projects and the Glomar Explorer (Ship), 1975-1976, undated
          - National Security Council, 1948, 1976, undated
        - Mahlmann, Rainer, and Freedom of Information Services, Inc., 1975-1976, undated
        - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and related material, 1974-1980, undated
        - “National Information Policy,” report, 1976 (Box 88)
        - National Science Foundation, 1976
        - National Security Council, 1976
        - Nuclear Regulatory Commission, 1975
        - Parole Commission, 1972-1976, undated
        - Privacy Act, 1975-1976
        - “Project Haven,” 1976, undated
        - “Reactions of Foreign Citizens and Groups,” report, 1979
        - Selective Service System, 1976
        - Smithsonian Institution ruling, 1976
        - State Department, 1976
        - Statistical data, 1975-1976, undated
        - Steward, W. Donald, blackmail allegations, 1974-1976
        - Transportation Department, 1975-1976 (Box 89)
        - U. S. House of Representatives, Government Information and Individual Rights Subcommittee (Abzug Committee), 1975-1976, undated
        - Wallace, James R., speeches, 1976
    - Succeeding articles
      - Business exemptions, 1978-1981, (2 folders)
      - Center for National Security Studies, 1978-1985, undated
      - Central Intelligence Agency
        - Miscellany, 1979-1983
        - U. S. Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, hearings, 1981
      - “Day in Support of Freedom of Information,” 1982
      - FBI “break-in” files dispute (Box 90)
        - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1975, 1981-1982
        - Research material, 1941-1942, 1950-1958, 1966, 1975-1981, (2 folders)
      - “Freedom of Information Improvements Act of 1981,” 1981
      - Freedom of Information Reform Act, 1983
      - Justice Department, 1977-1983, undated
      - Miscellany
        - Correspondence, 1978-1983
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1980-1983
      - National Campaign to Save Freedom of Information, 1981-1982
      - Proposed amendments and reforms (Box 91)
        - Articles and notes, 1981-1983
        - Research material, 1981-1983, undated, (2 folders)
      - Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press, 1980-1981
      - Society of Professional Journalists, 1981-1983
      - State Department, “Biographic Register,” 1980
      - U.S. House of Representatives, Government Information and Individual Rights Subcommittee, hearings, 1981
        - Research material
          - Miscellany
          - Statements and testimony, (2 folders)
          - Statements and testimony (Box 92)
      - U.S. Senate Subcommittee on the Constitution, hearings, 1981
        - July 15
        - Oct. 15
        - Nov. 12
        - Dec. 14
  - Gambling See Containers 197-198, Public gaming (Box 93)
  - Gates, Robert, congressional confirmation, director of CIA
    - Articles, 1991
    - Interviews, 1991
    - Notes on Alan Fiers, 1991
    - Research material
      - Contra operation, 1986, undated
      - George, Clair E., 1990-1991
      - National Security Archive, chronology and documents, 1991
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1991, undated
      - Secord, Richard, 1990-1991
      - Steele, James, 1986-1991
      - U.S. Senate Select Committee on Intelligence hearings, 1991
        - Press conferences
        - Statements
        - Transcripts
          - Sept. 16
          - Sept. 17, (8 folders) (Box 94)
          - Oct. 3
          - Oct. 4-Nov. 5, (3 folders) (Box 95)
  - Georgia Senate race, 1972
  - Gingrich, Newt, opposition to gun control, 1994-1995, undated
  - Government employees, removal from office, 1966-1980, (2 folders)
  - Gramm, Phil
    - Articles, 1976
    - Correspondence, 1996
    - Corsicana, Texas, property, 1990-1995, undated
    - Doyle, William Henry, 1971-1979, 1995, undated
    - Gramm, Wendy, 1983-1996, undated
    - Gramm-Rudman Bill, 1985-1990 (Box 96)
    - Notes, undated
    - Presidential campaign
      - Financial disclosures, 1995
      - Matching fund application, 1995, (2 folders)
    - Research material
      - Democratic Committee publication, circa 1995
      - Legal documents, 1995
      - Miscellaneous, 1976-1979, 1992-1996
      - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - 1961, 1972-1989
        - 1990 Oct.-1995 July, (7 folders) (Box 97)
        - 1995 Aug.-1996 Feb., undated, (4 folders) (Box 98)
    - Senatorial financial disclosures, 1987-1993, (3 folders)
  - Hammer, Armand, 1989 (Box 99)
  - Haiti, lists of classified documents in the Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, Austin, Tex., 1964
  - Hart, Gary See also Containers 5-9, Campaign spending, 1984 national election campaigns
    - Articles, 1983-1985
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984, undated
    - Interviews, 1983-1984
    - Jackson, Jesse
      - Articles and correspondence, 1984, undated
      - Interviews and notes, 1984
      - Research material, 1983-1984, undated, (3 folders)
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-1984, undated, (3 folders)
      - Notebooks (Box 100)
        - 1983
        - 1984
          - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders)
          - Mar.-Apr., (3 folders) (Box 101)
          - May-July, (2 folders) (Box 102)
        - Undated
        - Undated (Box 103)
    - Research material
      - Campaign financial disclosures, 1978, 1983-1984
      - Itineraries, 1983-1984, undated, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1973, 1983-1984, undated, (2 folders)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - 1968-1983, (3 folders)
        - 1984
          - Jan.-Feb.
          - Mar.-Oct., (2 folders) (Box 104)
        - Undated
      - Speeches, 1981-1984, (5 folders)
  - Howard Hughes Medical Institute, 1972-1976, undated
  - Hubbell, Webb, sentencing, 1994-1995, undated
  - Hughes, Howard, death (Box 105)
    - Articles and correspondence, 1976, undated
    - Interviews and notes, 1973-1975, undated
    - Research material, 1975-1977
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., hospitalization, 1976
  - Interpol
    - Articles and notes, 1988
    - Research material, 1982-1988, undated
  - Iran
    - Articles and notes, 1989-1990
    - Graves, John E., former hostage
      - Articles and correspondence, 1981
      - Research material, 1974, 1981
    - Rajavi, Kasem, assassination
      - Articles and notes, 1990, undated
      - Research material, 1983-1990, undated
    - Research material
      - Hostages in Lebanon, 1988-1990, undated, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1987-1990, (3 folders)
      - Woodward, Bob, and Dan Morgan, papers received from (Box 106)
        - Articles, undated
        - Correspondence, 1976-1980, undated
        - Legal documents, 1977-1980, undated, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1967-1978, (4 folders)
          - 1977-1978, undated, (2 folders) (Box 107)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1958-1989, undated, (2 folders)
        - Notes
          - Miscellaneous, 1976-1979, undated, (2 folders)
          - Notebook, undated
  - Iran-Contra Affair See also Containers 170-173, National Security Agency; Containers 177-187, North, Oliver, and Container 227, Toobin, Jeffrey
    - Abrams, Elliott, 1991
    - Articles, 1969-1979, 1986-1991, undated
    - Bush, George (Box 108)
      - Articles and interviews, 1992-1993, undated
      - Notes, 1993, undated
      - Research material, 1986-1993, undated, (3 folders)
    - Clarridge, Duane R., 1987-1992
    - Correspondence, 1986-1991
    - Fernandez, Joseph F.
      - Articles and notes, 1988
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1987-1989, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1988-1989 (Box 109)
    - Fiers, Alan D., 1986-1991, undated
    - Gates, Robert M., 1987-1991, undated
    - George, Clair E.
      - Articles, 1992, undated
      - Notes, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents
          - Exhibits, 1986, (2 folders)
          - General case material, 1990-1992, undated, (3 folders)
          - Juror communications, 1992 (Box 110)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1960, 1992, undated
    - Gesell, Gerhard A., 1962-1971, 1988, undated
    - Gregg, Donald P.
      - Correspondence and notes, 1986-1991, undated
      - Research material, 1986-1991, 1997, undated, (4 folders)
    - Indictments
      - Articles, 1988-1989, undated
      - Research material
        - Miscellaneous, 1988, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1987-1990, undated
    - Kerry, John F., 1986
    - McFarlane, Robert C.
      - Legal documents
        - Exhibits, 1984-1985
          - No. 54
          - Nos. 58-60, (3 folders) (Box 111)
          - No. 62
          - No. 67
        - General case material, 1988
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1987
    - Meese, Edwin, 1986-1988
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1986-1990, undated
      - Notebooks
        - 1987
          - Jan.-Mar.
          - Apr.-Nov. (Box 112)
        - 1988-1991, undated, (4 folders)
    - Research material
      - Coverup: Behind the Iran Contra Affair, 1988-1991, undated
      - Freedom of Information Act requests, 1986-1988
      - Legal documents (Box 113)
        - Deposition, Ronald Reagan, 1990, (2 folders)
        - Exhibits, 1985-1992, undated
          - Nos. 100-118
          - No. 119
          - Nos. 120-173
        - General case material
          - 1984-1987, (3 folders)
          - 1988-1989, undated, (5 folders) (Box 114)
      - Miscellaneous
        - 1973, 1984-1986, (3 folders)
        - 1987-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 115)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - 1964-1986, (3 folders)
        - 1987, (2 folders)
        - 1987, (2 folders) (Box 116)
        - 1988-1991, undated, (2 folders)
    - Reports
      - "Fourth Interim Report to Congress by Independent Counsel for Iran/Contra Matters," 1993, (2 folders)
      - "Fourth Interim Report to Congress by Independent Counsel for Iran/Contra Matters," 1993, (2 folders) (Box 117)
      - Tower Commission, 1987
      - U. S. Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, 1986-1987, undated
    - Secord, Richard V.
      - Notes, 1989
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1987-1989, (3 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1987-1989, undated
    - Waite, Terry, 1986-1991, (2 folders) (Box 118)
    - Walsh, Lawrence E., and staff
      - Articles and correspondence, 1986-1993, undated
      - Interviews and notes, 1986-1991, undated, (6 folders)
      - Research material (Box 119)
        - Legal documents, 1955, 1972-1987, undated, (3 folders)
        - Miscellaneous, 1935, 1944, 1955, 1970, 1976-1993, undated, (3 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material
          - 1954, 1961, 1971-1986
          - 1987-1994, undated, (2 folders) (Box 120)
  - Iraq
    - Banca Nazionale del Lavoro, Atlanta, Ga., branch
      - Articles and correspondence, 1992
      - Notes, 1978, 1990-1992
      - Research material
        - General, 1990-1992
        - Legal documents, 1991-1992, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1989-1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 121)
    - Nuclear weapons
      - Articles and correspondence, 1990
      - Notes, 1990
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1990
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1986-1990, undated, (3 folders)
  - Iraqi pipeline
    - Articles, 1987-1988, undated
    - Book proposal, "Crime in High Places," 1988
    - Notes, 1988, (2 folders)
    - Research material (Box 122)
      - Attorneys' memoranda, 1988
      - Freedom of Information Act requests, Justice Department, 1988
      - Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, 1983-1987
      - Legal documents, 1985-1986, (3 folders)
      - Meese, Edwin
        - Deposition, 1987-1988
        - Lewin, Nathan
          - Correspondence, 1988
          - Statements by counsel, 1988
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1987-1988, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1984-1988, undated
      - Overseas Private Investment Corp. (OPIC), 1985-1987, (2 folders) (Box 123)
      - Rappaport, Bruce
        - Appointment calendars, 1984-1985, (2 folders)
        - Indexes to subpoenaed documents
          - Independent counsel interviews, 1988
          - Office files, 1988
        - Interviews by FBI, 1988
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1977-1988, undated
        - Professional fees, 1984-1986
      - Wallach, E. Robert
        - Indexes to subpoenaed documents, 1988, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1988, undated
        - Office files, 1985-1986, undated
  - Irish Republican Army, undated (Box 124)
  - Israel, 1972-1990
  - John Birch Society
    - Articles and correspondence, 1971-1976, undated
    - Interviews, 1976, undated
    - Notes, undated
    - Research material
      - American Opinion, 1971-1976
      - Anti-Defamation League of B'Nai B'rith, studies, 1964-1976
      - Blue Book, 1959
      - John Birch Society Bulletin, 1976, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1962-1976, undated
      - Reports, 1972-1975 (Box 125)
      - Review of the News, 1976
      - Tax Reform Immediately Committee, 1976
  - John Paul II, Pope, assassination attempt, 1982
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., undated
  - Jonestown mass suicide, Jonestown, Guyana
    - Articles and correspondence, undated
    - Interviews, 1977-1978, undated
    - Notes, 1978-1979, undated
    - Research material, 1978, undated
  - Jordan, Hamilton, drug use investigation
    - Articles, 1979-1980, undated
    - Correspondence, 1979, undated
    - Interviews, 1979, undated
    - Notes, 1977-1979, undated
    - Research material
      - Legal documents, 1979-1980, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - 1978
        - 1979-1980, undated, (4 folders) (Box 126)
      - Report of the special prosecutor, 1980
  - Jordan, Vernon E.
    - Articles, 1980, undated, (2 folders)
    - Interviews, 1980, undated
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1980, undated
      - Notebooks, 1980, undated
    - Research material (Box 127)
      - Miscellaneous, 1973, 1980, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1979-1981, undated, (5 folders)
  - Kennedy, Edward Moore
    - Chappaquiddick Island, Mass.
      - Articles, 1969-1970, 1979, undated, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980, 1989, undated, (2 folders)
      - Interviews, 1979-1980, undated
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1969-1980, undated, (2 folders)
        - Notebooks, 1979-1980, undated, (2 folders) (Box 128)
      - Research material
        - Freedom of Information Act request, 1979
        - Miscellaneous, 1970, 1979, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material
          - 1969-1979, (2 folders)
          - 1980, 1989, undated (Box 129)
    - Personal wealth
      - Articles, 1979, undated
      - Correspondence, 1979, undated
      - Interviews, 1979, undated
      - Notes, 1978-1980, undated
      - Research material
        - Blind trusts, 1960, 1978, undated
        - James M. Landis Papers, 1932-1954, undated
        - Monkeen Oil Co., 1978-1980
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1961-1979, undated, (2 folders)
        - New York corporate records, 1979 (Box 130)
        - Tax returns, 1974-1979
  - Kennedy, John F.
    - Assassination See also Containers 231-239, U. S. House of Representatives, Select Committee on Assassinations
      - ACCESS, campaign for release of records, 1980-1983, undated
      - Acoustical study
        - Articles, correspondence, and notes, 1979-1981
        - Research material, 1965, 1980-1982
      - Allen v. Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1981-1983, (2 folders)
      - Autopsy, 1963-1977, undated
      - Belin, David, 1975, undated
      - Bronson, Charles, film, 1963, 1978, undated (Box 131)
      - Commission on CIA Activities within the United States (Rockefeller Commission), 1967-1975, undated
      - Davidson, Jean, Oswald's Game, 1983
      - Eddowes, Michael, The Oswald File, 1977
      - Epstein, Edward Jay, Legend: The Secret World of Lee Harvey Oswald
        - Article, 1978
        - Correspondence and interviews
          - Hoch, Paul L., 1978 See also Container 133, same heading
          - Weisberg, Harold, 1972-1978, undated
        - Miscellany, 1962, 1975-1978, undated
        - Notes, undated
        - Research material
          - Freedom of Information Act requests
            - About Epstein, 1966, 1976-1977
            - By Epstein, 1963-1964, 1976-1978
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1978
          - Reader's Digest excerpts, 1978
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1964, undated
      - Ferrie, David, death of, 1967, 1975, undated
      - Garrison, Jim, investigation (Box 132)
        - Bradley, Eugene E., arrest warrant, 1967-1968
        - FBI file, 1963-1978
        - General
          - Articles, 1967, undated
          - Correspondence and notes, 1967-1970, undated
          - Research material
            - Miscellaneous, 1955-1956, 1964-1968, undated
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1963-1970, 1978, undated, (2 folders)
      - General
        - Articles, 1967, 1975-1980, undated
        - Correspondence
          - Freedom of Information Act requests, 1975-1984
          - Hoch, Paul L., 1975-1980, 1988 See also Container 131, same heading (Box 133)
          - Miscellaneous, 1950, circa 1972-1986, undated
          - Morrow, Robert D., 1976-1991
          - Moss, Armand, 1984
          - Weisberg, Harold, 1971-1984, undated, (2 folders)
        - Notes, 1977-1981, 1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 134)
        - Research material
          - Congressional investigations, 1975-1976
          - Freedom of Information Act requests
            - Central Intelligence Agency
              - Lists, circa 1975-1976, (2 folders)
              - Released documents
                - Miscellaneous, 1948-1976
                - Numerical file (Box 135)
                - Documents 1-605, (8 folders)
                - Documents 608-664, (4 folders) (Box 136)
                - Documents 665-915, (6 folders) (Box 137)
                - Documents 916-1221, (6 folders) (Box 138)
                - Documents 1222-1363, (3 folders) (Box 139)
            - Commission on CIA Activities within the United States (Rockefeller Commission), 1960-1964, 1975, (2 folders)
            - Federal Bureau of Investigation, released documents
              - Fair Play for Cuba Committee, 1961-1979
              - Miscellaneous, 1963-1979, 1995, undated, (4 folders)
              - Numerical file (Box 140)
                - Documents 1-352, (7 folders)
                - Documents 363-498, (4 folders) (Box 141)
                - Documents 608, 1669, and 1698
              - Oswald, Lee Harvey
                - Reports 1-65, 1964-1968
                - Trip to Mexico, 1963-1964, undated
              - Oswald, Marina, 1961-1963
              - Ruby, Jack, 1963-1964
            - Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, Austin, Tex.
              - 1976-1980, undated, (4 folders) (Box 142)
            - Military records, 1960-1964, 1977-1978, 1988
            - Secret Service, 1955-1963, undated, (5 folders)